<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="493" moduleid="2997" modulename="page" contextid="3787">
  <page id="493">
    <name>Mathematical Practices Checklist</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Option to view/download the Mathematical Practices Checklist&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Guidelines and Purpose for Using the Math Practices Checklist&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Th&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b style="line-height: 16.0030002593994px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.231;"&gt;e Math Practic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;b style="line-height: 16.0030002593994px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.231;"&gt;es Checklist provides instructors a vehicle for reflecting on the educational value and affordances of each OER and activity beyond the mathematical content being addressed. By identify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b style="line-height: 16.0030002593994px;"&gt;&lt;b style="line-height: 16.0030002593994px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.231;"&gt;ing relevant mathematical practices, teachers become mindful of how they are asking learners to spend their limited education time and thus become purposeful in their instructional decision making. As a by-product of this process, participating teachers will become intimately acquainted with and thoughtful about the CCR Math Standards or other standards used to guide instruction. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;b style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;&lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Mathematical%20Practices%20Checklist.docx" title="Mathematical Practices Checklist"&gt;Download the Checklist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b style="line-height: 16.0030002593994px;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/OpenMath_MathChecklist.JPG" width="194" height="228" alt="Mathematical Practices Checklist" style="margin: 3px 6px; border: 1px solid black; float: right;" /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;b style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Using This Checklist&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Identify the OER and lesson goals at the top of the page.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Once an OER has been identified as potentially useful, be sure to list the OER and lesson goals at the top of the page. Use the checklist to identify the mathematical concepts, procedures, real-world applications, and mathematical practices that could be developed by using the OER. This process requires an instructor to ask the following questions regarding the identified OER:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;1) Does the OER support the development of mathematical concepts, mathematical procedures, or real-world applications? These are listed as the first three categories on the checklist.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;2) Does the OER support the development of any of the Mathematical Practices listed in the second half of the checklist? Please note that Mathematical Practice #7 on the checklist combines two of the Mathematical Practices (#7 and #8) from the &lt;em&gt;College and Career Readiness Standards for Adult Education.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Although no single OER will likely meet all lesson goals, using the checklist to check off the corresponding OER with a checkmark, an “X,” a “yes,” or a “no” will help identify any gaps or omissions. If any key mathematical concepts or practices are not met, then an additional OER or other complementary/supplemental activities should be added. The last column identifies any complementary or supplemental activities needed to complete the lesson. These activities could precede, surround, or follow the implementation of the OER to meet the instructional goals for learning. Be sure to consider how the complementary activities might be used to develop additional mathematical practices and note which additional practices are being met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The checklist tool will help keep key mathematical concepts and practices in an easily accessible, easy-to-use format as OER lessons are created. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:1:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>11</revision>
    <timemodified>1477518938</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>